What I've really done is create the best
algorithm for completing a construction
project while managing all actions as
they happen with detailed for reports
and feedback loops to confirm the
process is complete. A lot of people
have asked how my app works and how it
does renovation. So, I picked you guys
to show it to. We are at 2639 Royal
Street. The first house I ever renovated
top down on an application. Here's how
it works. This is the manager panel.
Nobody's seen this yet. They just have
the mobile applications, client and
vendor. You want to see what this place
looked like when we started? You see?
So, one bathroom, back room where the
laundry room is now. That's where we
started. And so, here's what I started
with. Interior demolition.
Francisco did it for $1,900. He gutted
this house out.
Wow. I assigned tasks like this. Gut out
bathroom, kitchen,
replace exterior door, $200.
How much does it cost to install a metal
roof? I paid $2,800 in labor. How much
was the metal?
Here's the receipt. The metal cost me
$2,340.89.
I know when it was bought. I have my
warranty. I know what kind it is. I have
the item number. I know who installed
it. I have before pictures. To bid this
job, send your labor price and include
your metal roofing material list in your
work description.
I don't have to come to this job. You
give me the material list and your price
and pictures of what you're going to do.
And per the contract you sign, if you
buy anything on my account, you have to
upload the receipt to this. If you
don't, I can withhold the amount of the
receipt from your pay until you do. It
really teaches your guys to think. That
is my end goal. I want to run the
business, but I really want to improve
my people while I do it.
What's the app called? Fail's house.
Fail's house.
All projects begin with a detailed scope
of work. Data transmission. This is what
we all are doing at the start. This is
what this house looked like at the
start.
Here's what we're doing. Description
pictures. Here's my blueprint with the
bathroom edition. See how descriptive it
is?
Yeah.
And it goes down the whole thing so
everybody knows the entire game plan
from the start. This one was really
tough cuz look at the size of the
bathroom. You ever seen a shower door
like this? All of this is masonry walls
with 2x4s nailed on. It took me all day
to do these three doors. I paid myself
$300 to trim this house out. I got it
done late. I was penalized $99. Had to
figure out a way to incentivize people
properly. Give them a deadline. It's
assigned in the task before it starts.
We're not wasting 3 days. You're getting
a notification three times a day within
3 days of your deadline. I'm not texting
anybody. a construction worker, a $100
bill means something.
That's a lot. If you're past your date,
you just hit a button and you send me
what dates you want and why. And I
approve them every time. My goal is not
to fee you. It's to make you pay
attention. This is where the chimney was
that Francisco was supposed to tear
down. That was the wall. The chimney was
here. And here's your closet. You see
how this is off to the side? This is
that closet right here. And we had to
cut out some of it, but leave some of
it. Problem in construction is data
transmission. You look how detailed I
am.
Wow.
Written in their native tongue with a
mark. All you have to do is draw a level
line. I have a button. I can hit it at
any point. It says download report. The
project summary. I spent $38,147.20
in labor, $10,77.99
in material. 34 assigned jobs. Interior
demolition, 1900, landscaping, 1800. You
can assign tasks as well. Jobs have
pavement. Tasks are just assigned with
no payment. $50,000.
Uh-huh.
In this. And I paid $9150 for it. How
much do I have invested? $60,000. This
is about to rent for $1250 a month. How
long will it take me to get my money
back in a perfect world with no account
for
about 5 years?
A little less. This is directly linked
to QuickBooks. Everything that happens
financially here is in a QuickBooks
account. Client panel. You want to get a
quote? Boom. Look at this. Hey, for
solar projects, click here. And what
does it ask for? Everything I need to
know. The clients be notified of every
step without me doing anything. I'm no
longer a message passer. Calendar view.
You can see all of the tasks. You can
toggle them on and off by project. With
this app, I've eliminated the need for a
secretary, somebody to answer their
phones, a bookkeeper, and just a record
keeper. What I've really done is create
the best algorithm for completing a
construction project while managing all
actions as they happen with detailed for
reports and feedback loops to confirm
the process is complete. That is how I
conceptualize my mission.